{
    "id": "efafcc116cbd4fc798effe2fc7a21f96",
    "title": "Can or Could | Grammar Exercise",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "6c0f918edd0449d1b19e1da171cfc44d",
            "title": "Can or Could | Grammar Exercise",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "........................... I ask you something?",
                    "description": "Both can and could are possible here. Could is more polite than can.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Can",
                        "Could",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "She said I ............................ come as often as I liked.",
                    "description": "When the main clause is in the past tense, we need a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
                    "answers": [
                        "can",
                        "could",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Jack ................................. not go to work yesterday because he was ill.",
                    "description": "Could is the past tense form of can. Here the time expression yesterday clearly indicates that we are referring to the past. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "can",
                        "could",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "He ............................. borrow my car, if she asked.",
                    "description": "In conditional clauses, if the verb in the if-clause is in the past tense, we use could / would / might + infinitive in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "can",
                        "could",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I .................................... her, if I had wanted to.",
                    "description": "When the verb in the if-clause is in the past perfect tense, we use would / could have + past participle in the main clause. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "could marry",
                        "could have married",
                        "can marry"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": ".......................... you lend me some pounds until tomorrow?",
                    "description": "Both can and could are possible here.",
                    "answers": [
                        "Can",
                        "Could",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "When I was a child, I ............................ play whenever I wanted to.",
                    "description": "",
                    "answers": [
                        "can",
                        "could",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "'Where is John?' He .......................... be in the garden.",
                    "description": "Can is not used in affirmative sentences to talk about logical possibility. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "can",
                        "could"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It was a place where anything .......................... happen.",
                    "description": "We use could here because the main clause is in the past tense.",
                    "answers": [
                        "can",
                        "could",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I ............................ not understand anything she said.",
                    "description": "We use could here because the verb in the other clause is in the past tense.",
                    "answers": [
                        "can",
                        "could",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "You ............................ get a better job if you speak English.",
                    "description": "When the verb in the if-clause is in the present tense, we use will / can + infinitive in the main clause",
                    "answers": [
                        "can",
                        "could"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "War ............................ break out any day.",
                    "description": "Can and could are possible here could shows weak possibility. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "can",
                        "could",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}